WEBVTT
Kind: captions
Language: en

00:00:00.240 --> 00:00:05.920
Welcome to introduction to witchcraft
everybody. This is lesson one. So this

00:00:03.679 --> 00:00:13.599
slide occurs at the beginning of every
class. We very rarely do this slide out

00:00:09.679 --> 00:00:18.880
loud. I'm going to do it today. I use it
when honestly for me as the teacher

00:00:16.240 --> 00:00:22.400
sometimes when we start class I'm like
not really in the zone. Like there's

00:00:20.640 --> 00:00:26.160
stuff going on in my life that I'm
anxious about or whatever and I need

00:00:24.000 --> 00:00:29.760
help like now it's time for learning
witchcraft. And that's what this prayer

00:00:28.000 --> 00:00:33.120
is. So, I'm going to do it out loud, but
we don't normally do it. It just sits in

00:00:31.439 --> 00:00:37.760
the slides if anybody ever wants to do
it for yourself. So, it goes like this.

00:00:35.440 --> 00:00:41.680
Blessed goddess of the crocco, you are
limonality who keeps the doors of

00:00:39.920 --> 00:00:47.200
initiation. And so many call you
propilia or she who stands before the

00:00:44.079 --> 00:00:52.239
gates. You are liberation who helps us
freely choose. And so many call you

00:00:49.440 --> 00:00:56.079
triadus or she of the forked path. You
are a goddess of learning who guides us

00:00:53.920 --> 00:01:00.640
from ignorance to understanding. And so
many call you Didalos or she who knows.

00:00:58.719 --> 00:01:06.640
Blessed goddess of the crocco. In the
name of Python Draena, I ask be with me

00:01:03.840 --> 00:01:10.880
now as I open my mind. This is
introduction to witchcraft 13 lesson.

00:01:08.560 --> 00:01:15.119
Oh, okay. This class used to be called
13 lessons in practical spellcraft. But

00:01:13.119 --> 00:01:19.680
on the advice of my publisher, it is now
called 13 lessons in the practice of

00:01:17.119 --> 00:01:25.360
magic, which is a better name. Good job,
guys. This is lesson one. We say it's

00:01:22.320 --> 00:01:30.080
about color and candle magic, but really
I think this class is about like opening

00:01:28.159 --> 00:01:34.880
your heart and soul to the wonder of
magic. Like that's the big theme of

00:01:31.920 --> 00:01:40.320
today's lesson. So I'm Sarah Mastros.
Please call me Sarah. I guess you can

00:01:36.880 --> 00:01:44.320
call me teacher Sarah if you want. I
like that's good. I've been practicing

00:01:42.320 --> 00:01:47.280
witchcraft for it says 30 years, but
obviously these slides are 10 years old,

00:01:45.840 --> 00:01:51.759
so I suppose about 40 years at this
point. Um, I used to teach university

00:01:49.520 --> 00:01:55.600
and then high school math and then I
quit to be a degenerate with no real

00:01:53.520 --> 00:01:58.960
job, which is going great for me. I've
written a bunch of books, including the

00:01:57.439 --> 00:02:02.560
one the textbook for this course, which
is not on this list because I failed to

00:02:00.560 --> 00:02:07.200
update the slide.
Our divine patron for this class, if

00:02:05.439 --> 00:02:10.319
you're into that, but if you don't, just
if you're not, don't ignore it. It

00:02:09.200 --> 00:02:15.680
doesn't really matter. Like, it's not
central to the class, is Thoth, the

00:02:12.879 --> 00:02:19.760
great teacher of teachers, right? So,
he's an ibis headed. Ibis is a kind of

00:02:17.680 --> 00:02:24.879
an aquatic bird kind of like a stork or
a crane. If I had to say I would say

00:02:22.879 --> 00:02:29.120
Ibis is like a cross between a stork and
a goose. We don't have ibises where I

00:02:27.040 --> 00:02:32.959
live. Right. So Ibis had an Egyptian
scribal god. He's a lunar god of the

00:02:31.440 --> 00:02:36.480
crocco peplo which it doesn't matter
what that means. You'll learn in a later

00:02:34.400 --> 00:02:41.120
class. And occasionally he's going to
pop up like this image will pop up and

00:02:38.560 --> 00:02:45.200
there'll be like a a bubble here and
he'll like give you advice that is not

00:02:43.360 --> 00:02:50.480
really about magic. It's just about what
as a teacher we would call studentship.

00:02:47.920 --> 00:02:54.800
Okay. He's an ibis. So the way his voice
sounds in my head, my human throat

00:02:52.800 --> 00:02:59.840
cannot make that noise, but I'll do my
best. It goes like

00:02:57.280 --> 00:03:03.440
most important
because he's like a goose crane and

00:03:01.440 --> 00:03:08.879
that's what he sounds like. But I can't
make the right noise because I have a

00:03:05.680 --> 00:03:13.200
human throat and not an throat. So this
course, as I mentioned, is for adults

00:03:10.640 --> 00:03:17.120
only. If you are a parent, you are
welcome to have your child sitting next

00:03:15.200 --> 00:03:20.720
to you as long as you are also in the
room. I will tell you for people who

00:03:19.120 --> 00:03:25.200
want to do that, the lessons on
planetary magic have a little bit of sex

00:03:22.879 --> 00:03:30.319
magic in them that I personally and I'm
a like witchy libertine do not really

00:03:27.920 --> 00:03:34.080
feel like as appropriate for kids. But
other than that, maybe some naughty

00:03:32.000 --> 00:03:37.680
words. In my opinion, far more
appropriate than regular prime time

00:03:35.840 --> 00:03:42.239
television where people are like getting
their guts pulled out or whatever.

00:03:39.840 --> 00:03:46.400
Everyone is welcome here. If you are a
beginner, you should think about this

00:03:44.400 --> 00:03:49.840
course that your goal is to like learn
fundamental skills that you can then

00:03:48.239 --> 00:03:53.680
take into whatever kind of magic you
want to do. If you think of yourself as

00:03:51.840 --> 00:03:57.920
like intermediate, right? You've been
practicing for a while, but you would

00:03:55.680 --> 00:04:02.640
not consider yourself advanced, then I
think the best thing to do is look for

00:03:59.360 --> 00:04:05.280
the like look to fill the gaps, right?
Like you know some stuff and you don't

00:04:04.080 --> 00:04:09.840
know some stuff. Look to fill those
gaps. And also like I encourage you to

00:04:07.599 --> 00:04:12.720
come at it with like a fresh and open
mind which is also true for advanced

00:04:11.120 --> 00:04:17.840
people but for intermediate people
right? If you consider yourself advanced

00:04:15.599 --> 00:04:22.560
then I think you should try and pretend
that you are a beginner in this class

00:04:20.639 --> 00:04:26.320
because at least for me like I consider
myself an advanced sorceress. Like I've

00:04:24.400 --> 00:04:29.120
been doing this for a long time. I teach
it. I take your money to teach it. So

00:04:27.919 --> 00:04:33.280
it' be pretty sad if I didn't think I
was advanced, right? Sometimes I feel

00:04:31.280 --> 00:04:37.840
kind of stuck and stagnant and I just
want something new to like break me out

00:04:34.880 --> 00:04:41.520
of a rut. And if that's you, I think the
best way to do that is try and come at

00:04:39.360 --> 00:04:46.800
everything with like a beginner mind.
That being said, this class is designed

00:04:43.520 --> 00:04:50.720
for and like centered on beginner level
teaching, which means that like

00:04:49.040 --> 00:04:54.880
sometimes somebody's going to ask a
question and I might say that's a little

00:04:52.720 --> 00:04:57.360
too advanced for this class and then
I'll tell you like ask it in the

00:04:56.320 --> 00:05:01.440
Facebook group and we'll talk about it
there. No prerequisites for this class

00:04:59.600 --> 00:05:07.280
except you probably should be fluent in
English because I talk pretty fast. This

00:05:04.720 --> 00:05:11.440
class is also available in Italian and
traditional Chinese like with a human

00:05:09.600 --> 00:05:16.400
translator in Italian and traditional
Chinese, but I assume you speak English

00:05:14.000 --> 00:05:18.880
if you're here already. Every month
you're going to receive it says a

00:05:17.440 --> 00:05:23.039
written chapter, but that's false.
There's a textbook. You have a textbook.

00:05:21.120 --> 00:05:28.240
You'll get a Zoom lecture. It says about
three hours. They're rarely shorter than

00:05:26.080 --> 00:05:32.320
two and they're never really longer than
four, but about three hours. This one I

00:05:30.720 --> 00:05:35.680
think is this one's a little long
because there's all this like boring

00:05:33.600 --> 00:05:41.039
syllabus stuff at the beginning. You'll
get a video of the lecture. Uh there's a

00:05:38.960 --> 00:05:45.680
human being named Caroline who edits the
videos. So sometimes she has a life and

00:05:43.759 --> 00:05:49.919
it takes a little longer than a week. If
it's been more than a week and the

00:05:47.360 --> 00:05:54.560
video's not up, please email me because
usually she's not the one who's late.

00:05:52.320 --> 00:05:58.720
She said it to me and I failed to put it
like I failed to put it in the syllabus.

00:05:56.320 --> 00:06:02.320
If it's late, I apologize. I'm gonna
tell you guys the worst thing about me

00:06:00.400 --> 00:06:07.440
as a teacher is I'm kind of sloppy and
disorganized.

00:06:04.160 --> 00:06:11.120
Sorry, I'm an ADD magician. So, I think
honestly I'm less sloppy and

00:06:08.960 --> 00:06:16.240
disorganized than most of my colleagues.
Okay, if you do all of the homework,

00:06:13.600 --> 00:06:22.240
like if you do everything I tell you to
do, then in addition to the four hours

00:06:18.720 --> 00:06:27.360
of class, it's probably 10 to 15 hours
of work on your own. For most people, I

00:06:25.039 --> 00:06:31.840
actually don't recommend doing it. Like,
do whatever catches your fancy. For most

00:06:29.759 --> 00:06:36.160
people, I think the best way to go
through this class is to take it once

00:06:34.080 --> 00:06:41.280
and like not do a very good job. like
take it, watch the videos, you know, do

00:06:38.880 --> 00:06:46.080
any homework that seems fun and not the
rest of them. And then if at the end of

00:06:43.520 --> 00:06:50.880
the class you still want to deep dive,
go back and take it again. In terms of

00:06:48.800 --> 00:06:54.080
pricing, once you've paid for this
class, you're just in this class for

00:06:52.639 --> 00:06:57.440
well, I don't want to say forever. I
mean, I'm going to die at some point.

00:06:56.000 --> 00:07:01.520
You're going to die. Like, it's not
eternal, but you're in this class until

00:06:59.440 --> 00:07:06.880
either I stop teaching this class or you
tell me to take you out of this class. I

00:07:04.319 --> 00:07:13.360
strongly encourage you guys to keep like
a magical journal. And some people get

00:07:10.639 --> 00:07:17.919
really precious about their magical
journal. I am not encouraging to you to

00:07:15.440 --> 00:07:22.080
make like a super fancy beautiful book
of shadows grimmooire that's like bound

00:07:19.680 --> 00:07:26.240
in fetal goat skin. That kind of art
project is fun and if you're into that,

00:07:24.000 --> 00:07:29.199
go for it. I'm kind of into that. Like I
like that. But I'm just saying like a

00:07:27.599 --> 00:07:33.759
sloppy journal where you just take
notes. just whatever you think about,

00:07:31.759 --> 00:07:38.560
whatever you research your exercises,
write it all down. There is a Facebook

00:07:36.240 --> 00:07:44.080
group which is the primary group like
discussion group for this class. I'm

00:07:42.160 --> 00:07:49.280
trying to move it off Facebook because
Facebook is a toxic cess pit

00:07:46.639 --> 00:07:51.520
and also getting worse day by day.
Yeah,

00:07:49.599 --> 00:07:55.039
there is also a Discord group, but
nobody uses it.

00:07:53.440 --> 00:07:58.080
I'm looking for other options. So, if
people have ideas, please send me an

00:07:56.400 --> 00:08:04.000
email. like I would like to get this
class off of Facebook and somewhere else

00:08:00.879 --> 00:08:08.240
before Facebook implodes.
The I the in the Facebook group, it's

00:08:06.479 --> 00:08:11.199
not just this class, it's all my
classes, which I like. It's kind of one

00:08:09.840 --> 00:08:17.599
room schoolhouse, right? So beginner
students and advanced students are all

00:08:12.960 --> 00:08:20.960
in the group together, right? And if you
watch the questions and answers, you'll

00:08:19.280 --> 00:08:26.560
be able to sort out who's a beginner and
who's not pretty quick, right? But I

00:08:23.919 --> 00:08:30.319
very much encourage discussion. I am of
the opinion when I am asked what is the

00:08:28.400 --> 00:08:36.159
my single piece of advice for beginner
magicians. It is get a com magician.

00:08:34.320 --> 00:08:43.360
Like it's not that I have some moral
objection to solitary practice but like

00:08:40.959 --> 00:08:49.200
Talmud says in terms of like studying
Jewish stuff that studying alone makes

00:08:45.920 --> 00:08:53.360
you stupider. Like I just think partners
and working together with other people

00:08:50.800 --> 00:08:58.640
one is good for the soul to like engage
with other human beings ideally without

00:08:56.080 --> 00:09:02.480
a robot in between you like in the same
room together but if you can't do that

00:09:00.399 --> 00:09:08.399
on the phone online I just think it's
good practice it helps people learn and

00:09:05.760 --> 00:09:13.680
it's fun
okay beg you to read the syllabus every

00:09:11.600 --> 00:09:17.519
if you email me about logistics I'm
going to answer it but I assure you any

00:09:15.680 --> 00:09:23.040
question you have about like when is
class, what's the Zoom link? It's there.

00:09:20.080 --> 00:09:26.240
It's all in the syllabus. Um, which is
that that's the document I sent out

00:09:24.560 --> 00:09:30.399
called like welcome to introduction to
witchcraft. Everything you need is in

00:09:27.920 --> 00:09:35.200
there, but I'm always here. I'm a nice
person. You're welcome to contact me at

00:09:32.480 --> 00:09:40.320
any time. What I do ask is that you
please not use Facebook Messenger for

00:09:37.760 --> 00:09:44.480
course stuff because Facebook Messenger
is where I talk to my friends. And if

00:09:43.360 --> 00:09:49.360
every time I'm trying to talk to my
friends, my job, my work, I get work

00:09:47.279 --> 00:09:54.560
messages over and over and over, it's
like hard to have a life, right? So, if

00:09:52.880 --> 00:09:58.240
you have a question about content, like
you have a question about witchcraft,

00:09:56.240 --> 00:10:02.399
the best place to ask it is either in
class or in the Facebook group because

00:10:00.399 --> 00:10:05.600
that way like you can get answers from a
lot of people, including, you know, many

00:10:04.480 --> 00:10:09.440
other professional teachers of
witchcraft. Like Jason Miller's in that

00:10:07.360 --> 00:10:13.760
group, BJ Swain is in that group. So,
like they'll answer your questions too

00:10:10.800 --> 00:10:16.800
sometimes if they feel like it. I'll
tell you I answer questions in their

00:10:15.200 --> 00:10:21.279
classroom groups when I'm bored
basically. Um,

00:10:19.600 --> 00:10:23.760
but also that way everybody can learn
together. Like everybody gets to learn

00:10:22.640 --> 00:10:28.240
from your question. If you have a
question about logistics, please email.

00:10:25.839 --> 00:10:31.760
But again, I I beg you don't send work
messages to my Facebook Messenger.

00:10:30.240 --> 00:10:36.079
Please. I mean, if you do, I'll be nice
and answer them. But also,

00:10:34.880 --> 00:10:39.839
if you send something Facebook
Messenger, either I'm going to answer it

00:10:37.600 --> 00:10:43.680
right away or never. Where if you send
it by email, like my email box is like a

00:10:42.000 --> 00:10:47.519
to-do list. I will eventually like
chuggle through.

00:10:45.600 --> 00:10:51.920
As I mentioned before, I am sloppy and
disorganized. So, if I miss an email,

00:10:50.000 --> 00:10:58.240
like you should always feel free to nag
me. I apologize for being ADD and

00:10:55.600 --> 00:11:02.079
disorganized. My dream in life is to
have like a gaggle of secretaries who

00:11:00.079 --> 00:11:07.440
just follow me around and organize my
life for me. That's that's my dream.

00:11:04.880 --> 00:11:11.680
Problem is everybody I like is like the
sort of people who are uptight and have

00:11:09.680 --> 00:11:15.360
everything like are really good at
organizing. They I don't really get on.

00:11:13.920 --> 00:11:19.519
I will say so I mentioned this before.
Caroline who edits the videos is not a

00:11:18.000 --> 00:11:25.440
secretary but like does help. And I also
have an assistant named Alice who every

00:11:22.560 --> 00:11:30.079
once in a while does stuff like
I don't think you guys ever notice

00:11:27.279 --> 00:11:35.680
anything she does. She does like backend
like paperwork kind of stuff for me. So

00:11:32.959 --> 00:11:39.920
probably you'll never hear about her,
but maybe she'll send you like the

00:11:37.760 --> 00:11:44.959
Google calendar.
She made that. She's 22 and like knows

00:11:42.959 --> 00:11:49.680
how computers work better than I do. So
she really does that for me. As I said

00:11:47.839 --> 00:11:55.360
before, I really encourage people to
find a study buddy to like partner with.

00:11:52.720 --> 00:12:01.040
The easiest thing to do is just ask in
the Facebook group, right? But, you

00:11:58.720 --> 00:12:04.079
know, there are 400 people in this
class. So, hopefully you can find a

00:12:02.560 --> 00:12:07.519
study buddy that like you can work out
times with. If you don't like to use

00:12:06.079 --> 00:12:11.920
Facebook, which is totally legitimate
because as I mentioned, it's a toxic

00:12:08.800 --> 00:12:16.240
cess pit. Um, if you email me, I will
hook you up with the next person who

00:12:13.760 --> 00:12:21.519
emails and asks. But like I can't
matchmate. I'm just gonna kind of give

00:12:18.800 --> 00:12:25.120
you somebody and if you don't get along,
I don't know, find somebody else. Don't

00:12:23.440 --> 00:12:27.839
get along is usually not personal. It's
usually like you're in different time

00:12:26.399 --> 00:12:31.279
zones and you can't get the schedule to
work or something like that. Okay. So,

00:12:29.600 --> 00:12:34.560
we're going to move into like actually
getting to learn some witchcraft now.

00:12:33.200 --> 00:12:38.639
So, this is just a quote from Redard
Kipling. It goes, "I've had six faithful

00:12:36.320 --> 00:12:43.200
serving men who taught me all I know.
Their names are what and why and when

00:12:40.639 --> 00:12:47.360
and how and where and who." And Thoth
says, "Asking questions is the best way

00:12:45.040 --> 00:12:52.079
to learn." Honk talk.
There we go. So, we're gonna talk a

00:12:49.839 --> 00:12:57.200
little bit about the styles of magic you
learn. So, sometimes on like, okay,

00:12:55.200 --> 00:13:00.880
sometimes I'm just hang out in beginner
witch groups on Facebook and answer

00:12:59.200 --> 00:13:05.200
questions. And sometimes I ask questions
like, "What kind of witch am I?" And I

00:13:02.880 --> 00:13:10.240
don't I don't know. I've been a witch
for 35 years at this point. I mean, in

00:13:09.040 --> 00:13:14.079
some ways I've been a witch since I was
born, but like I've been identifying as

00:13:12.320 --> 00:13:18.959
a witch for 35 years and I don't know
what kind of witch I am. I'm the Sarah

00:13:16.320 --> 00:13:23.360
Mastros kind, right? So, I'm going to
try and teach you like a sampler of all

00:13:21.279 --> 00:13:28.480
different methods. So, if you're in a
class and you see a lesson and like it

00:13:26.320 --> 00:13:31.040
just doesn't seem like your style, well,
the next lesson is going to be a

00:13:29.839 --> 00:13:37.040
different style. I tried to do a
sampler. Of course, it is biased towards

00:13:33.839 --> 00:13:40.480
the kinds I like best. And what the the
most important thing you need to know

00:13:38.240 --> 00:13:45.680
about my style is that I'm a nerd and I
like nerd magic. So there's a lot of

00:13:42.639 --> 00:13:50.000
like poetry and like numerology and like
nerd [&nbsp;__&nbsp;] in my magic because I'm into

00:13:47.839 --> 00:13:55.200
that. You'll see as we go through this
class, right? I try to keep this class

00:13:52.320 --> 00:14:01.120
what I call paradigm agnostic, which is
to say even though sometimes I'll like

00:13:57.839 --> 00:14:06.000
reference like gods, there's really no
religious content in this class. You

00:14:03.760 --> 00:14:10.079
don't really have to believe anything.
It doesn't really matter what you

00:14:07.279 --> 00:14:15.920
believe. I'm going to say that sometimes
as we get very much later in the class,

00:14:14.079 --> 00:14:21.440
like when I'm teaching you how to
conjure a spirit in a mirror

00:14:19.360 --> 00:14:26.000
to make it work the way I teach it, you
probably do have to at least be able to

00:14:24.160 --> 00:14:29.839
convince your you need to be able to
pretend that you believe spirits are

00:14:27.920 --> 00:14:34.959
real for approximately an hour at a
time. But even that you don't have to

00:14:31.839 --> 00:14:39.199
believe until like lesson 10 or 11. Just
to be clear, this is not a class on

00:14:37.040 --> 00:14:44.639
Wikah, which is a religion, a religion I
do not practice. This is not a class on

00:14:42.160 --> 00:14:47.839
traditional witchcraft. How about a
traditional witch? Like kind of yes,

00:14:46.399 --> 00:14:51.920
kind of no. It depends. Like I don't
think traditional witchcraft has a very

00:14:49.120 --> 00:14:56.880
clear definition. I am certainly a witch
and the witchcraft I practice is very

00:14:54.560 --> 00:15:01.680
traditional but sometimes the phrase
traditional witchcraft means something

00:14:58.880 --> 00:15:06.720
more specific that I'm not exactly. This
class is not about like religion or

00:15:04.639 --> 00:15:13.760
beliefs or anything like that although
sometimes those come up right is a class

00:15:10.320 --> 00:15:18.880
is a craft class like the witchcraft is
the craft that witches do like craft in

00:15:16.639 --> 00:15:24.880
this context means like profession like
you do stuff right you make stuff right

00:15:22.560 --> 00:15:29.360
and the stuff that witchcraft you're
making is resultsoriented spell work

00:15:27.120 --> 00:15:34.399
like I'm going to teach you to do spells
that will make changes is in the world.

00:15:32.079 --> 00:15:39.600
Not just in your heart and mind, but
also out in the world, right? But also

00:15:36.959 --> 00:15:43.920
in your heart and mind. And again, the
goal of this class for me as a teacher

00:15:42.160 --> 00:15:47.839
is to teach you fundamental skills so
that you could go to any when we talk

00:15:45.519 --> 00:15:52.639
about like kinds of magic that you could
just show up at say a Golden Dawn ritual

00:15:50.800 --> 00:15:57.279
and know what's going on. Like you can
follow what's going on by the end of

00:15:54.160 --> 00:16:02.240
this class. you can go to like a voodoo,
right, and like understand what is going

00:16:00.560 --> 00:16:06.399
on, right? Like that's not to say you're
an initiate in those things, but like

00:16:04.480 --> 00:16:12.639
you you know what's what. Like you have
you're basically fluent in magic. That's

00:16:08.959 --> 00:16:16.959
the goal of this class, right? So the
specific skills you're going to learn,

00:16:15.040 --> 00:16:21.360
this is just the curriculum. So today
we're going to learn candle color and

00:16:18.720 --> 00:16:27.519
petition magic. Next month we're gonna
learn sympathetic magic and about like

00:16:24.240 --> 00:16:30.320
magical materials. And it says amulets.
We're going to learn a little bit about

00:16:28.800 --> 00:16:34.560
amulets, but truthfully most of the
amulet stuff is in lesson three, which

00:16:32.399 --> 00:16:39.839
is about like symbols basically.
Talisman, sigils, seals, symbols, right?

00:16:37.839 --> 00:16:43.920
Um, and then divination. I'll tell you
that historically I taught divination

00:16:41.600 --> 00:16:46.880
and then symbols and my editor was like,
"Hey Sarah, that's dumb. You should take

00:16:45.519 --> 00:16:50.160
symbol." I mean, she said it. They said
it nicer than that, but like, yeah,

00:16:48.880 --> 00:16:54.399
obviously I should have been teaching
symbols before divination, so now I do.

00:16:52.480 --> 00:16:58.160
Lesson five is about the sun and the
magic of the sun and the moon. Lesson

00:16:56.160 --> 00:17:01.600
six is the rest of the planets. There
used to be one planetary lesson, but it

00:16:59.920 --> 00:17:06.720
was like five hours long, so I split it
into two lessons. Lesson seven is about

00:17:04.000 --> 00:17:11.120
centers and circles. Lesson eight is
about cleansing and protection. Lesson

00:17:08.799 --> 00:17:14.959
nine is about cursing and also curse
breaking because you can't learn to

00:17:12.799 --> 00:17:18.480
break curses until after you learn to
cast curses. It's actually easier to

00:17:16.880 --> 00:17:22.240
curse someone than it is to break a
curse. So, you kind of have to learn

00:17:19.839 --> 00:17:26.079
cursing first. Lesson 10 is all about
dreaming and dream magic, which is a

00:17:24.000 --> 00:17:29.760
favorite topic of mine that in my
opinion other like just doesn't get

00:17:27.839 --> 00:17:33.919
taught. And I I don't know why people
don't talk about dream magic. I think

00:17:32.400 --> 00:17:38.480
people should talk about it more. I
think it's amazing. Uh lesson 11 is

00:17:36.160 --> 00:17:42.400
trance journey. Lesson 12 is
shapeshifting. Although I'm going to

00:17:39.840 --> 00:17:45.919
tell you, the last time I taught it, I
felt like it didn't go very well. So, I

00:17:43.919 --> 00:17:50.799
might tweak it around a little bit. Um,
and then lesson 13 is dark mirror

00:17:47.919 --> 00:17:54.320
conjuration. So, the art of summoning a
spirit in a I do it in a dark mirror,

00:17:53.039 --> 00:17:57.360
but you could also do it like in a
crystal ball. It's basically the same

00:17:55.760 --> 00:18:02.160
technique.
For me, that's the thing I learned that

00:17:59.520 --> 00:18:06.240
made me feel like a real grown-up badass
witch. Like the first time I could

00:18:03.919 --> 00:18:10.480
conjure a spirit and have a face-tof
face conversation with a spirit in a

00:18:08.559 --> 00:18:14.240
mirror,
I felt like a badass magician. So that's

00:18:12.880 --> 00:18:17.520
when I thought about what do you want
what I want people to be able to do in

00:18:15.760 --> 00:18:21.679
some sense like this course is to
prepare you to be able to do that,

00:18:20.000 --> 00:18:25.200
right? But you learn tons of other cool
stuff along it. So the first thing we're

00:18:23.840 --> 00:18:29.600
going to learn and you're going to learn
o over the yearong that we're going to

00:18:27.679 --> 00:18:34.240
study together. You're going to learn a
lot of different ways to like enter into

00:18:32.080 --> 00:18:39.600
magical consciousness, which you we
could also call like tramps or like not

00:18:37.679 --> 00:18:43.360
all altered states of consciousness are
magical consciousness. There's lots of

00:18:41.280 --> 00:18:46.559
different kinds, but like we're going to
learn a lot of different kinds. The one

00:18:45.120 --> 00:18:52.080
we're going to work with today is
childlike wonder, which in my opinion is

00:18:49.440 --> 00:18:54.400
honestly one of the best ones for magic.
And I think people don't talk about it a

00:18:53.600 --> 00:18:58.799
lot because they think it's
embarrassing. Like it's like silly to

00:18:56.640 --> 00:19:04.160
behave like a child, but that's dumb.
That's just dumb. Right? So the essence

00:19:01.760 --> 00:19:07.280
of the magic
that we're going to learn today, not

00:19:05.760 --> 00:19:11.520
through the whole course, but today is
that we're going to play make believe.

00:19:09.280 --> 00:19:16.559
Right? And we're going to do that until
we make ourselves believe it. And then

00:19:14.720 --> 00:19:20.480
we're going to keep doing it until we
make other people believe it. And then

00:19:18.880 --> 00:19:25.280
we're going to keep doing it until the
universe believes it, too. That is the

00:19:23.280 --> 00:19:30.000
essence of the kind of magic we're going
to do today, which I personally just

00:19:27.520 --> 00:19:36.080
call makebelieve magic, but other people
would give other pretentious names, too.

00:19:33.520 --> 00:19:40.000
The most important thing that you need
for this kind of magic is to not be

00:19:37.919 --> 00:19:45.120
ashamed of yourself. You can't be like,
"Oh, I'm too cool to pretend I'm an

00:19:41.919 --> 00:19:51.360
eight-year-old. I'm too cool to like say
magic rhymes and wish for things." Like,

00:19:49.280 --> 00:19:55.280
you're not too cool. You're not cool
enough. Like if you're too cool for

00:19:53.200 --> 00:19:58.480
magic, I believe you to be not cool
enough for magic. But I know I'm

00:19:57.039 --> 00:20:01.919
preaching to the choir because you guys
literally paid to be in this choir. Most

00:20:00.480 --> 00:20:07.200
of you, many people are on scholarship,
right? So shame. The thing you have the

00:20:04.799 --> 00:20:11.520
thing if you if the magic we I teach you
today doesn't work. The most likely

00:20:09.760 --> 00:20:15.280
reason is that you're ashamed of
yourself because you think magic is

00:20:13.840 --> 00:20:19.679
silly because you think you're going to
go to hell. Some kind of reason. And I

00:20:18.000 --> 00:20:23.440
encourage you to like be on the lookout
for that. That being said, you signed up

00:20:21.919 --> 00:20:29.360
for a witchcraft class. You've probably
already made it over that hurdle,

00:20:26.400 --> 00:20:33.919
right? Okay. So,
the next piece of most magic, so almost

00:20:31.760 --> 00:20:39.520
all magic, step one is enter into
magical consciousness. Step two is enter

00:20:36.799 --> 00:20:44.159
into magical spaceime. And o you'll
learn lots of different kinds of magical

00:20:41.919 --> 00:20:47.679
spacetime. The kind we're going to do
today, which I believe to be the easiest

00:20:45.760 --> 00:20:53.600
kind. That's why I do it in lesson one.
I call standing at the sacred center.

00:20:50.559 --> 00:20:58.320
Many people call it centering,
but that word can mean a lot of

00:20:56.080 --> 00:21:02.400
different things. So, I'm going to call
it standing at the sacred center, but

00:21:00.400 --> 00:21:08.640
most people would call this centering. I
just think my name is clearer and I'm a

00:21:04.799 --> 00:21:12.000
fussy wizard, so I care about names.
Okay. The essence of standing at the

00:21:10.559 --> 00:21:15.520
sacred center, and we're going to learn
like details about how to do it. This is

00:21:13.520 --> 00:21:20.480
like the coming attractions, is that
your heart, by which I mean both like

00:21:18.240 --> 00:21:25.760
your metaphoric heart, like the seat of
your soul, but I also mean literally

00:21:22.880 --> 00:21:30.720
like the organ that pumps your blood,
you're that you should put that in the

00:21:28.240 --> 00:21:34.320
center of the universe. That's the
essence of standing at the sacred

00:21:32.559 --> 00:21:38.080
center, which we will talk about a
little bit more, but that's more or less

00:21:36.480 --> 00:21:44.640
what you're going to learn how to do. So
the first thing to do when you center is

00:21:40.960 --> 00:21:50.159
just like become aware of your body.
Just like move around a little bit. And

00:21:47.200 --> 00:21:54.320
my my teacher my one of my teachers
would have called this like airrating

00:21:51.840 --> 00:21:58.720
yourself, right? Like take some deep
breaths, move around, maybe dance a

00:21:55.919 --> 00:22:02.640
little. Like get yourself in your body.
Then whenever you're ready, you're going

00:22:00.000 --> 00:22:08.159
to stand up nice and straight or like
you know sitting down is also fine, but

00:22:05.679 --> 00:22:13.039
like try and keep your spine vertical.
If for whatever reason like you have to

00:22:10.400 --> 00:22:17.760
lay on your back, that's okay, but it is
easier to do this with your spine

00:22:14.960 --> 00:22:22.159
vertical. That is like your head pointed
toward the sky and your feet pointed

00:22:20.000 --> 00:22:27.120
toward the center of the earth. Right?
Close your eyes.

00:22:24.960 --> 00:22:30.000
Just breathe slow and deep. We're not
going to do this right now. like I'm

00:22:28.480 --> 00:22:35.679
going to teach you how to do this, but
we're not going to do it in class. If we

00:22:32.880 --> 00:22:41.039
if in class we did every piece of magic
we were going to learn, then every class

00:22:38.240 --> 00:22:44.960
would be like 20 hours long. So that's
why we don't do it together, right? So

00:22:43.679 --> 00:22:50.720
you're just going to close your eyes,
breathe deep and slow, and then take

00:22:47.520 --> 00:22:55.120
your fist and put it on your sternum and
push on it. That really helps. that

00:22:53.520 --> 00:22:59.679
little trick I learned from Jason Miller
about like pushing on your sternum. It

00:22:57.520 --> 00:23:03.679
does help, right? So, put your fist on
your sternum and push with your other

00:23:01.200 --> 00:23:08.080
hand. Personally, I've used my left hand
for the fist and push with my right. I

00:23:06.000 --> 00:23:11.640
don't think it matters, right? And then
you're going to sing out

00:23:12.400 --> 00:23:17.840
and you're going to feel it in your
chest.

00:23:15.840 --> 00:23:22.000
I can't carry a tune in a bucket. So
sometimes people ask me what pitch I

00:23:20.159 --> 00:23:26.080
don't know like the pitch that feels
like it's in your chest is the only way

00:23:23.600 --> 00:23:30.880
I know how to answer that question,
right? And just do that a bunch of times

00:23:28.559 --> 00:23:34.159
until you can feel it vibrating in your
chest. Sometimes people will say

00:23:32.880 --> 00:23:39.120
something like like the Golden Dawn
sometimes has like vibrate a god name.

00:23:36.880 --> 00:23:44.640
It's not like a metaphor. Like you're
vibrating a piece of your body like

00:23:42.880 --> 00:23:50.000
like if you hit yourself, you can make
it vibrate really obviously, but you

00:23:47.600 --> 00:23:55.600
don't need it to be that obvious, right?
Vibrate, right?

00:23:53.200 --> 00:24:00.480
Okay. Next, you're going to you're going
to reach upward with your whole body.

00:23:57.919 --> 00:24:05.000
So, up on your tippy toes, reach up up
to the heavens. And here you're going to

00:24:02.000 --> 00:24:05.000
go

00:24:06.000 --> 00:24:13.120
in your head, right? Just do it however
many times you feel like you need to do

00:24:10.320 --> 00:24:18.400
it to like get it to fill up your head.
Basically, once you've done that, you're

00:24:15.679 --> 00:24:24.240
going to just like grab the heavens and
pull it down. And you're going to pull

00:24:21.120 --> 00:24:29.039
that down through the top of your head
and into your chest. And your chest

00:24:26.080 --> 00:24:32.240
should already be like lit up sort of
because you did that vibrating before.

00:24:30.799 --> 00:24:36.000
You're going to pull it down into your
chest, right? And then you're going to

00:24:34.400 --> 00:24:41.039
just keep going down. So, just like we
reached up, we're going to go down,

00:24:38.080 --> 00:24:45.200
right? But don't bend over. Like, don't
bow, don't lean, keep your back

00:24:43.039 --> 00:24:51.200
straight, but reach down with your hands
as low as you can. Bend your knees. You

00:24:49.360 --> 00:24:55.679
know, I'm a fat old lady and my ability
to like squat is and then get back up is

00:24:54.080 --> 00:25:01.440
not that good. Like, I use a cane. My
knees, my left knee in particular is

00:24:58.000 --> 00:25:07.000
like not right. Right. But just push
down with your body. And then you want

00:25:03.840 --> 00:25:07.000
to sing

00:25:09.200 --> 00:25:16.080
and you should feel it vibrating in your
genitals or maybe like your lower belly,

00:25:14.159 --> 00:25:20.320
but like that part of your body. And
just do it. And then right and just like

00:25:18.559 --> 00:25:25.919
you pull down the heavens, you're going
to pull up hell. Pull up the underworld.

00:25:23.760 --> 00:25:29.520
Pull it up through your bum and up your
spine and into your chest. So now the

00:25:27.440 --> 00:25:34.159
heavens and the underworld have like
combined in your chest.

00:25:32.320 --> 00:25:38.320
If you're really good at this, you could
just stop here, but we're learning. So

00:25:37.039 --> 00:25:43.039
we're going to do it a couple times,
right? Just going to do it a couple of

00:25:39.919 --> 00:25:46.520
times. For a while, you want to go top,
middle, bottom.

00:25:48.400 --> 00:25:54.720
For right now, I encourage you to simply
think of those as sounds that you are

00:25:52.400 --> 00:25:59.520
making. But if you're a nerd, they are
also the ancient Greek what we would

00:25:56.320 --> 00:26:03.279
call barbarous magical name. Yao yao
like the correct that is what we're

00:26:01.440 --> 00:26:09.080
doing. But that's you don't need to know
about that. Just the sound. Focus on the

00:26:06.080 --> 00:26:09.080
sound

00:26:09.840 --> 00:26:12.840
right.

00:26:13.840 --> 00:26:20.480
Do it a bunch of times. Play around with
how fast we're going to spread a

00:26:17.279 --> 00:26:25.679
rainbow. Like I will say broadly the
answer to your question is your body is

00:26:23.200 --> 00:26:30.240
going to become a rainbow pillar with
red at the bottom and violet at the top.

00:26:28.640 --> 00:26:35.360
Like it's an electromatic spectrum in
that order, but we'll talk about that a

00:26:32.400 --> 00:26:38.880
lot more. But good question. Um again,
so you want to like do it a bunch of

00:26:37.039 --> 00:26:47.200
times and like play around with the
pacing. And then you can also play

00:26:40.960 --> 00:26:52.159
around with the order like uh uh o e
o uh like play around, right? And you

00:26:50.000 --> 00:26:56.320
want to get fluent at doing this like
fast and easy. So just play because

00:26:54.240 --> 00:27:01.279
right now we're just learning, right? We
haven't actually done anything really,

00:26:59.600 --> 00:27:07.120
right? We're just sort of prepping
ourselves, right? We're like energizing

00:27:04.240 --> 00:27:11.679
our body. So whenever you're, you know,
you're ready to go, like keep playing

00:27:09.200 --> 00:27:15.600
around, feel the energy move around.
When you feel like you're full of light,

00:27:14.080 --> 00:27:19.120
and for some people that might be
visual, like you might be able to see

00:27:17.120 --> 00:27:22.720
your aura, right, light up. And for
other people, it might be like a for me

00:27:20.720 --> 00:27:29.039
it's more of like a physical sensation
in my body. Kind of like getting chills

00:27:26.240 --> 00:27:32.240
but slower. kind of like I don't know if
this is true for men or not but my

00:27:30.960 --> 00:27:36.960
experience and I think most women is
that orgasm can kind of ripple across

00:27:34.880 --> 00:27:41.919
the body and that's kind of the feeling
you're looking for probably not that

00:27:39.520 --> 00:27:45.600
intensely right but whenever you feel
like you're full of light whether you

00:27:43.520 --> 00:27:50.559
can see it or not some people will never
be able to like see it visually

00:27:48.159 --> 00:27:54.000
musicians sometimes experience I will
say musicians have told me that

00:27:52.480 --> 00:27:59.039
sometimes when they do this what they
experience is like a chorus of angels

00:27:56.960 --> 00:28:03.120
making singing with them, like making
those sounds with them. But I think

00:28:00.880 --> 00:28:06.799
we're all kind of experiencing the same
phenomenon. We're just experiencing it

00:28:04.799 --> 00:28:12.080
in different ways. So for me, it's a
quite physical like vibration kind of

00:28:10.000 --> 00:28:17.520
tingle in my body, but there's no like
visual component to it for me, which is

00:28:15.120 --> 00:28:21.919
why like what color I don't know. Mine
aren't colors at all really when I do

00:28:19.200 --> 00:28:27.360
it. There's just like a vibration.
Okay. So, just like we went up and down,

00:28:24.399 --> 00:28:34.000
now we're going to go front and back,
right? So, I always do front first and

00:28:31.200 --> 00:28:39.600
then back. But you could do it however
you want, right? So, just like you reach

00:28:36.240 --> 00:28:44.399
high up, reach high as far front as you
can and pull that into you. I personally

00:28:42.799 --> 00:28:48.799
don't make a sound at all when I do
that, but if I was gonna, it would

00:28:46.080 --> 00:28:53.679
probably still be ah like everything on
this slide because it's kind of in your

00:28:50.240 --> 00:28:56.640
chesty region, right? Like in your heart
that I would use the a sound, but I

00:28:55.360 --> 00:29:00.080
actually don't make a sound at all when
I do this. Right? So, you're going to go

00:28:58.720 --> 00:29:04.320
just like you pulled from above and
below. You're going to pull them in from

00:29:01.600 --> 00:29:09.440
the front and the back. Again, I
typically do front first and then back.

00:29:07.840 --> 00:29:13.520
I don't actually think it matters which
order you do front and back in. So, you

00:29:11.919 --> 00:29:19.520
can try both and see what feels better
to you. Left and right. I pretty much

00:29:16.720 --> 00:29:23.120
always go left and then right. I'm
right-handed, but again, I don't

00:29:21.840 --> 00:29:27.200
actually think it matters what order you
eat them in. But I do think it's

00:29:24.480 --> 00:29:32.320
important to first go up, down, and then
front, back, and then left, right for

00:29:30.399 --> 00:29:37.120
like biological reasons, right? So,
human beings are not even remotely

00:29:35.279 --> 00:29:42.480
up, down, symmetric. Like the top of
your body and the bottom of your body

00:29:38.320 --> 00:29:46.880
are completely different shapes, right?
The front of your body and the back of

00:29:44.320 --> 00:29:50.320
your body are like more similar than up
and down are, but they're still very

00:29:48.320 --> 00:29:53.840
different. And then left and right,
you're not left right symmetric either,

00:29:52.320 --> 00:29:58.799
but like you're more left right
symmetric than front back symmetric. I'm

00:29:57.120 --> 00:30:02.799
going to say almost all humans. Like
even if you're missing an arm, I would

00:30:00.080 --> 00:30:06.080
tell you're still more right, left
symmetric than you are front, back

00:30:04.399 --> 00:30:11.520
because internally you're pretty
symmetric, right?

00:30:08.480 --> 00:30:15.520
So these six directions, up, down,
front, back, left, right, that when I

00:30:14.000 --> 00:30:20.399
say six directions, those are the ones
I'm talking about, right? And you're

00:30:17.440 --> 00:30:24.960
going to pull all those energies in and
like feel the mix. And when you're new

00:30:23.039 --> 00:30:29.200
at this, this can take a long time. Like
this ritual that I'm teaching you, the

00:30:27.279 --> 00:30:33.039
first couple times you do it can easily
take 20 minutes or half an hour to do,

00:30:31.520 --> 00:30:37.440
but once you're good at it, you'll be
able to do it really fast. It's just

00:30:34.799 --> 00:30:41.360
practice. It's just practice. I mean,
some magic is about skill, some magic is

00:30:39.440 --> 00:30:46.799
about talent, but this one just
practice, right? So now you're going to

00:30:44.480 --> 00:30:52.240
try and ex like you're going to breathe
in. And when you do, I want you to

00:30:48.880 --> 00:30:57.760
expand your body or your aura or however
you think about it. Your sensory bubble,

00:30:55.279 --> 00:31:01.919
expand it outwards in all six directions
at once, like a balloon blowing up,

00:30:59.760 --> 00:31:08.000
right? All directions at once. And then
breathe out and like shrink back.

00:31:05.440 --> 00:31:11.120
Breathe in and get big. Breathe out and
get small. And you know how when you're

00:31:09.919 --> 00:31:15.200
going to blow up a balloon, you like
stretch it first? That's really what

00:31:13.520 --> 00:31:20.240
we're doing. We're like stretching out
your energetic body to prepare. Like we

00:31:18.159 --> 00:31:24.720
still haven't really done any magic yet.
This is all we're just like getting

00:31:21.600 --> 00:31:30.080
ready to do magic. This is the important
step of centering. You've been

00:31:27.360 --> 00:31:36.080
stretching, expanding, and contracting.
Keep contracting down until you're like

00:31:32.720 --> 00:31:42.399
your consciousness, your unice is a tiny
little ball in the center of your body.

00:31:38.880 --> 00:31:48.320
And I need you to know for a fact that
that is the center of the universe.

00:31:46.480 --> 00:31:52.159
Now, the universe does not have a
center. Like, it just doesn't. Some

00:31:50.960 --> 00:31:55.200
people would say the center of the earth
is the center of the universe, but

00:31:53.360 --> 00:31:58.320
that's false. Some people would say the
center of the sun is the center of the

00:31:56.480 --> 00:32:02.480
universe. False. Some people would say
the galactic center is the center of the

00:32:00.080 --> 00:32:07.279
universe. False. All of those things are
false. I do have a graduate degree in

00:32:04.799 --> 00:32:13.120
mathematics with a specialty in fancy
space-time geometry. I assure you the

00:32:10.159 --> 00:32:17.279
universe does not have a center. You can
put the center wherever you want it to

00:32:14.880 --> 00:32:21.039
be. What's the center is just about how
you kind of lay out your coordinate

00:32:19.039 --> 00:32:27.679
grid. And I want you to lay out a
coordinate grid with your heart at the

00:32:23.679 --> 00:32:32.960
center. An axis that goes up, down, an
axis that goes front, back and left,

00:32:30.399 --> 00:32:39.679
right. So these are internal directions
not east west and north south but front

00:32:37.120 --> 00:32:45.840
back and left right. So as you turn the
entire coordinate like you're as if you

00:32:42.880 --> 00:32:50.640
were to turn around then what I want you
to imagine is that you're holding still

00:32:48.320 --> 00:32:56.240
and the entire universe is turning
around you which is true. Like that is a

00:32:53.760 --> 00:33:01.519
mathematical fact for any point anywhere
in the universe because movement is

00:32:58.880 --> 00:33:06.720
always relative. So like there's no like
this is really all you're reentering is

00:33:04.559 --> 00:33:10.640
really your understanding of the earth.
You didn't do anything to the universe.

00:33:08.559 --> 00:33:16.640
You didn't really even do anything to
your body except notice it like pay

00:33:13.760 --> 00:33:20.640
attention to it. Like like those energy
flows like the cord of energy that is

00:33:18.799 --> 00:33:25.360
now running from the heavens to your
heart. It it's actually always there.

00:33:23.600 --> 00:33:29.120
The ritual just made you pay attention
to it but it's always there. You didn't

00:33:27.039 --> 00:33:34.960
establish that chord. If you are a
living breathing creature, those cords

00:33:31.760 --> 00:33:38.320
are always there. It's just like they I
don't know everything's connected to

00:33:36.399 --> 00:33:42.080
everything else as we will discuss a bit
more later in the class.

00:33:39.600 --> 00:33:47.279
So that is centering, right?
And then what you typically we would

00:33:44.320 --> 00:33:49.760
center and then do some magic and then
let go. But this time we're just

00:33:48.720 --> 00:33:55.039
practicing. So we're just going to
center and then whenever you're done

00:33:52.159 --> 00:33:58.880
being centered, just let go. And you
should be able to just let go. Like it's

00:33:56.799 --> 00:34:02.480
actually pretty hard to stay centered.
It requires you to pay attention to it.

00:34:00.480 --> 00:34:07.360
So pretty much as soon as you stop
paying attention to it. It It's not

00:34:05.679 --> 00:34:12.000
you're not centered anymore. You're just
not noticing that you're centered.

00:34:09.919 --> 00:34:16.800
You're always centered. It like human
beings cannot be uncentered.

00:34:14.720 --> 00:34:20.720
Nor can anything else. Like that's just
not how the world works in my opinion.

00:34:19.119 --> 00:34:25.520
So it's really about what you're paying
attention to. Sometimes on the internet

00:34:23.200 --> 00:34:29.919
I see people say like magic is all about
intention and I don't think that's true.

00:34:28.000 --> 00:34:34.800
I actually think intention is like
barely relevant. What I think is

00:34:32.800 --> 00:34:40.480
important is attention. What are you
paying attention to? That's the secret

00:34:37.520 --> 00:34:43.599
sauce of magic is paying attention.
Right? Pay attention to what you're

00:34:41.839 --> 00:34:48.159
doing. Pay attention to who you are. Pay
attention to what you want. All of those

00:34:45.839 --> 00:34:52.560
things, right? But when you're ready,
just just be done. just stop do paying

00:34:51.200 --> 00:34:57.359
attention to it and just go back to your
regular however you normally live your

00:34:54.720 --> 00:35:00.960
life. Right? Move around. You might feel
like especially if you're good at this

00:34:59.599 --> 00:35:04.960
like not good you've practiced a lot but
you have a natural talent for it. You

00:35:03.040 --> 00:35:08.720
might feel like your body has like
stretched out like Alice and Wonderland

00:35:06.880 --> 00:35:12.160
style but if you just move around a
little bit you'll shake it off unless

00:35:10.560 --> 00:35:16.400
you're on a lot of drugs which is not a
wise thing to do. Like beginner

00:35:14.880 --> 00:35:22.480
magicians should not really be doing
magic on drugs. it like it's not wise.

00:35:20.079 --> 00:35:27.680
Yeah. Again, you're always centered. All
incarnate beings, everything that has a

00:35:24.560 --> 00:35:32.320
physical body, even if it's not alive.
Like a rock is also always centered.

00:35:30.640 --> 00:35:36.560
That's just what it means to be
incarnate, like to have a body. I

00:35:34.560 --> 00:35:41.119
encourage you if you are a beginner,
like if you really haven't done any

00:35:38.240 --> 00:35:44.880
magic before, in general, for everything
I teach you, I do encourage you to

00:35:42.960 --> 00:35:50.480
follow the instructions the first time
you do it. after you've done it a couple

00:35:47.599 --> 00:35:53.839
times, you should adapt it for yourself.
But if you've never done it before, I

00:35:52.480 --> 00:35:57.359
wrote the instructions because I think
that's the way that is best for

00:35:55.200 --> 00:36:01.760
beginners to do it. That being said, as
an advanced man, I actually don't do it

00:35:59.359 --> 00:36:05.920
that way exactly. Like that is how I
think beginners should do it. It's

00:36:03.119 --> 00:36:09.599
easier, but not exactly. So, if you have
experience, I don't know, do whatever

00:36:07.839 --> 00:36:13.359
you want to do, but you're in this
course because you want to learn my way

00:36:10.720 --> 00:36:18.160
of doing it, presumably because that's
the only kind of magic I can teach you

00:36:15.599 --> 00:36:23.200
is mine. That's the only kind I can
teach you, right? So, just a reminder

00:36:21.200 --> 00:36:28.240
that like if you're not sure if it's
working, it's kind of a fake it until

00:36:25.680 --> 00:36:32.000
you make it situation. Like make believe
that you can. So, if you don't know what

00:36:29.599 --> 00:36:36.160
I mean when I say it it feels like
you're lit up with like you're full of

00:36:33.839 --> 00:36:40.320
light, make believe that you're full up
with light, like what do you think it

00:36:38.560 --> 00:36:45.280
would feel like? And make believe that
really hard and then eventually it'll

00:36:43.440 --> 00:36:49.440
happen and you'll be like, "Oh, oh, that
that was real and not imaginary." And

00:36:47.839 --> 00:36:54.560
you'll be able to tell the difference.
You'll be able to tell. Everything we've

00:36:51.839 --> 00:36:58.400
done so far, I really would not
characterize as magic. I would

00:36:56.640 --> 00:37:03.280
characterize it as preparation for
magic. So, now we're going to start to

00:37:00.480 --> 00:37:09.760
talk about some magic. And the first
magic we're going to learn is color

00:37:05.040 --> 00:37:14.640
magic. I love colors. Every time I see
somebody make like magic art in black

00:37:11.920 --> 00:37:19.839
and white, in my heart, I'm like, that
is a missed opportunity for using

00:37:16.400 --> 00:37:24.560
colors. If you are color blind, I
apologize. This lesson is going to be

00:37:21.839 --> 00:37:28.560
pretty theoretical for you, but only
this one. So, you know, and I will say

00:37:27.200 --> 00:37:33.599
if you're color blind, I would actually
really like your feedback on this

00:37:30.400 --> 00:37:39.760
lesson, right? Which is primarily about
color blind, right? Our spectrum has

00:37:36.960 --> 00:37:44.640
seven colors. Red, orange, yellow,
green, blue, indigo, violet. When I say

00:37:42.480 --> 00:37:49.599
ours, I mean the English language. Like
that's how we label it in English. Does

00:37:47.440 --> 00:37:53.200
anybody want to guess why there are
seven in English? Not in every language.

00:37:52.160 --> 00:37:57.040
that like different languages have
different numbers but in English we use

00:37:54.480 --> 00:38:02.560
seven. So the answer is that the person
who like named the color spectrum in

00:37:59.280 --> 00:38:08.480
English like who decided that
indigo is a color but like blue violet

00:38:05.839 --> 00:38:12.240
is not one of the spectral colors. The
person who decided that was Isaac Newton

00:38:10.960 --> 00:38:17.040
in English. Like he's the one who
labeled them in English or the the

00:38:14.880 --> 00:38:20.240
labeling we typically use today was
invented by Isaac Newton. He was an

00:38:18.800 --> 00:38:24.720
alchemist. I know they didn't tell you
that in high school science class, but I

00:38:21.920 --> 00:38:29.119
assure you Isaac Newton was no question
a magician. If you just read I mean

00:38:27.040 --> 00:38:32.079
honestly probably his Wikipedia page
will tell you that he's an alchemist.

00:38:30.240 --> 00:38:35.920
Like it's not a secret, but they didn't
tell you that in high school because in

00:38:33.760 --> 00:38:38.800
my as a high former high school teacher
sometimes high school teachers seem

00:38:37.040 --> 00:38:43.599
really committed to making things
boring. Like Isaac Newton was a magician

00:38:41.760 --> 00:38:49.040
and they didn't tell you that which
would have been interesting. I imagine

00:38:46.079 --> 00:38:55.599
he chose seven so that he could assign
them to the seven classical planets used

00:38:52.320 --> 00:38:58.800
in alchemy and traditional western magic
which we'll talk about more in lessons

00:38:57.200 --> 00:39:03.839
five and six but that's why there are
seven in English before Isaac Newton I

00:39:01.839 --> 00:39:07.119
think there wasn't necessarily a clear
number like different people would just

00:39:05.440 --> 00:39:10.240
say it differently
okay

00:39:07.520 --> 00:39:16.560
and in other cultures so for example I
believe that in Russian there are 12 but

00:39:14.000 --> 00:39:20.079
I'm not positive. Like in other
languages there are other numbers and

00:39:18.240 --> 00:39:24.720
again it's a rainbow. How many colors
are in a rainbow? All the colors are in

00:39:22.560 --> 00:39:28.720
the rainbow but you have to chunk it
into bits to talk about. And like the

00:39:26.640 --> 00:39:33.440
question of is this green or is this
blue? Obviously there's like a bunch of

00:39:30.880 --> 00:39:37.839
colors in between. So when we teach
little kids there are seven colors. I

00:39:35.440 --> 00:39:42.720
mean obviously that is false. Like
there's way there's an almost infinite

00:39:41.359 --> 00:39:46.400
number of colors. We're going to talk
about seven. The reason in this class

00:39:44.560 --> 00:39:51.200
we're going to do seven is because we
are later on in the class going to tie

00:39:48.560 --> 00:39:55.599
them to the planets. A useful thing we
can do that was invented by Isaac. Like

00:39:52.880 --> 00:39:59.839
that magical trick. Like one weird trick
that makes your alchemy work is to label

00:39:57.680 --> 00:40:03.520
the rainbow so that it's actually
secretly corresponding planets. And

00:40:01.760 --> 00:40:08.560
that's an a trick I learned from Isaac
Newton and our culture learned from

00:40:05.520 --> 00:40:12.560
Isaac Newton. I don't I don't know what
it used to be in older English. In

00:40:10.560 --> 00:40:17.119
Greece, I believe in ancient Greek,
there's, I believe, five.

00:40:14.880 --> 00:40:19.839
Like, blue and green are not really
understood to be diff. I mean, it's not

00:40:18.800 --> 00:40:24.320
that they don't know the difference
between blue and green. They also have

00:40:22.640 --> 00:40:27.760
arguments. Is this blue? Is this green?
Is it green blue? Is it blue green? Blah

00:40:26.000 --> 00:40:30.480
blah blah. They can see all the colors.
Like, it's not like their vision is

00:40:29.200 --> 00:40:35.200
different than ours. They just have
different words for it. Sometimes I see

00:40:33.200 --> 00:40:37.040
like internet like ancient Greek people
didn't know about the color blue. I'm

00:40:36.720 --> 00:40:38.800
like,
oh god.

00:40:37.680 --> 00:40:43.359
But they did.
They did. They they call it wine. If

00:40:41.760 --> 00:40:46.160
you've ever seen the internet memes I'm
talking about, I'm going to tell you as

00:40:44.560 --> 00:40:50.800
a person who reads ancient Greek, when
they say the wine dark sea, they're

00:40:49.440 --> 00:40:55.040
actually not talking about the color at
all. They're saying the sea is drunk.

00:40:52.960 --> 00:41:00.480
It's drunk and that's why it's so wild
and violent and stormy. Like the way we

00:40:58.240 --> 00:41:07.040
would describe a an ocean as like
especially wavy when it's storming,

00:41:05.280 --> 00:41:10.720
they refer to that as the ocean being
drunk. When they say wine dark, they

00:41:08.880 --> 00:41:15.440
mean drunk. The same way that people's
faces turn darker when they're like

00:41:12.880 --> 00:41:21.760
excited and drunk. Why do I teach colors
first? It's because

00:41:18.000 --> 00:41:27.440
sometimes a lot teach like and vibration
magic first and it's I find it a little

00:41:24.480 --> 00:41:34.240
vague what they are talking about. Like
color is a vibration. That's how color

00:41:30.079 --> 00:41:38.240
works. Like it is an energy. Like and I
think color is like a good way to start

00:41:36.079 --> 00:41:44.319
with that. But color is also a good way
to learn to work with spirits. So like

00:41:40.960 --> 00:41:48.880
the spirit of the color red, I actually
think all of us already kind of have an

00:41:46.400 --> 00:41:52.720
idea what that spirit's going to be like
from just sharing a cultural

00:41:50.640 --> 00:41:58.800
understanding of the color red and
sharing even more so a biological

00:41:55.119 --> 00:42:02.079
understanding of the color red. Again,
if you're colorb blind, I'm interested

00:42:00.800 --> 00:42:07.119
because that means you have the cultural
one but not biological one. So, I'm

00:42:03.920 --> 00:42:07.119
interested in how this works for

